Papers of Andrew L. Riker and Family
Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library
Papers of Andrew L. Riker and Family
1844-1978
Andrew L. Riker and family
BHC-MSS 0004
26 manuscript box
Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library
The Riker family had considerable impact on Bridgeport in the early 20th century. Hired by the Locomobile Company of America, engineer Andrew L. Riker worked in Bridgeport for two decades His time as the chief of engineering and vice president of the Locomobile Company occurred at the same time that Bridgeport was producing seemingly everything, from heavy industrial products to small consumer goods. The papers of Andrew L. Riker and the Riker Family provide a look into how Riker himself functioned, how he worked, and what his private life was like. Materials also relate to his immediate and larger family, and help to offer a full picture of the family. Prominent within is material related to the early automobile industry, as well as family photographs and patents.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Biography
Andrew L. Riker was born on October 22, 1868 in New York City. He attended Columbia College with the intent to focus on law, but he took a keen interest in engineering. He began working within the automotive industry in 1884, and began his own company based in Elizabeth, New Jersey: the Riker Motor Vehicle Company. Also called the Riker Electric Motor Company, the manufacturer focused on building electric cars in the early days of the automotive industry. Eventually, Riker was lured to the Locomobile Company of America in 1902, which was based in Bridgeport, Connecticut. Over the course of his tenure there, he rose to the position of Vice-President of the company as well as the chief of engineering, but before that he gained recognition for developing gasoline cars for Locomobile. In 1908, the race car that he helped Locomobile to develop won the prestigious Vanderbilt Cup Race, which was given the number of 16 in the lineup. Old 16 was a major success, and represented Riker's skill in engineering and development. He also helped to develop the worm drive truck for Locomobile, which was later renamed the Riker Truck. This vehicle had a heavy presence in World War I, and the company produced a high number of the trucks for various allies in the war. Riker's professional life was marked by success. He helped to found the American Society of Automotive Engineers, and was heavily involved in a number of professional organizations. Until Locomobile began to close in the 1920s, Riker remained at the company. When Locomobile left Bridgeport, Riker retired, and settled into life in Fairfield, Connecticut. An active member of the community, he was a part of the town's planning commission. Together with his wife Edith Riker (nee Whiting) whom he married on April 9, 1890, Riker had three children: Edith W., Charlotte L., and Andrew L. Riker Junior. The family took numerous trips together, and Riker himself owned several yachts which he clearly took pride in. Andrew L. Riker died on June, 1930. The larger Riker family has been in the United States since the 1600s. There are living descendants of Andrew Riker today, and they are active in preserving their family's legacy as it relates to automotive history.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Andrew L. Riker and Riker Family Papers contain an eclectic variety of materials. The bulk of the material relates directly to Andrew L. Riker himself, and charts his career in the automotive industry, with a heavy focus on the 1900s to 1920s. While there is some manuscript material, most of it relates to his professional interests and contains things he either researched or was associated with. There are materials related to his personal life, but likewise they primarily reflect involvement and interests. Represented the most after Andrew L. Riker are materials related to Andrew L. Riker, Junior. His business records are presented to some degree, but the bulk of the material is research and correspondence relating to his father's history and the Locomobile Company. There are typed manuscripts of a draft of what might have been a book, as well as index card files.
Other members of the Riker family, including Riker's children with Edith, other children, and extended family have some manuscript material present. Photographs take up a large portion of the collection. A small group relates to the professional works and endeavors of Andrew L. Riker, the rest are family photographs. These include negatives that require conservation.
Due to the complex nature of the Andrew L. Riker and Riker Family Papers, the series has been divided into three sub collections: Andrew L. Riker, the Riker Family, and Oversize. The papers of Andrew L. Riker himself have been further grouped into two sub-groups: professional materials and personal materials.
Arrangement
Due to the complex nature of the Andrew L. Riker and Riker Family Papers, the series has been divided into three sub collections: Andrew L. Riker, the Riker Family, and Oversize. The papers of Andrew L. Riker himself have been further grouped into two sub-groups: professional materials and personal materials. Sub-group A begins with series I, which is composed of manuscript materials. Series II represents Riker's business ventures, and series III contains all patents issued to him. Series IV contains blueprints and drawings, and series V contains medals and ribbons Riker gained through various professional involvements over his lifetime. Series VII reflect the publications that Riker relied on to inform his own work, and series IX shows the maps he also collected as a part of his work. Series X represents clippings relating to Riker and his work, and series XI contains photographs related to his time in the automotive industry. Sub-group B collects the materials relating to Riker's private life. It contains manuscripts, material relating to his yachts, and also material relating to his death, funeral, and estate. Sub-collection B represents the material related to the rest of the Rikers. Series I contains material related to Edith L. Riker, Andrew's wife. His son, Andrew L. Riker Junior is represented in series II with a heavy emphasis on his research files and work. Edith and Andrew's daughter, Eleanor, has material represented in series III, and the rest of the family is chronicled in series IV. Series V contains photographs. Sub-collection C contains all oversize material.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Riker, A.L. (Andrew Lawrence), 1868-1930; Locomobile Company of America
- Series I: Andrew L. Riker manuscript materials
  - Book of letter copies, A.L. Riker, 1892-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Charles L. Seabury and Co. to Universal Electric Launch Co., 1894 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding the Inter-Ocean Automobile Show, Chicago, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Automobile Club of America, 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Hart O. Bergh (Riker’s European representative), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Whiting and Lawrence, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, A.L. Riker from Thomas Proctor regarding Electric Fire Engine, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, establishment of new company, 1900-1909 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Naval Consulting Board, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Aero Club of America, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Industrial Research Corporation, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Henry Ford Museum including donation of cars, 1924-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Typescript of Naval Board Digest, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Additional manuscript material, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bound book, blank, Andrew L. Riker, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II: Andrew L. Riker’s business ventures
  - Accounting, A.L. Riker, with J.S. and D.L. Riker, 1888-1902 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Electric Launch Company Catalogue, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes from Stockholders meeting of Universal Electric Launch Company, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Universal Electrical Launch corporation documents, 1893-1895 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Universal Electrical Launch insurance policy, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Universal Electrical Launch catalogue, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Universal Electrical Launch catalogue, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Riker Electric Motor Company catalogues, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Riker Electric Motor Company Electrical Apparatus for Marine Use, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Riker Electric Motor Company, brochure, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Riker Electric Motor Company and American Steel Casting Company contract, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Riker Electric Motor Company, Riker System for Electric Vehicles, 1888-1896 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Horseless Age, featuring Riker Electric Elizabeth NJ plant, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Motor Car and Motorcycle Exhibition held in London, featuring some electric cars powered by Riker design, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Riker Electric Vehicle Company, Announcement of opening of Elizabethport Plant, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Additional documents relating to Riker Electric Automobiles, 1890-1899 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Co., Receipts for European Patent Applications, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Contract for Sale of Foreign Patents to Riker Electric Vehicle Company, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Co., ads in Greater Interstate Fair in Trenton, NJ, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Riker Electric Vehicle Company, Vehicle data and electrics, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Riker Electric Vehicle Company, Tri-state Fair at Guttenberg, NJ, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Riker Electric Vehicle Company, press release, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Company, Directions for charging, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Company, Catalogue, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Company, Vehicle data announcements 1-41, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Catalog, Auto supplies, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Electric Vehicle Company. Columbia/Riker, containing the first mention of Riker Gasoline Car, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Electric Vehicle Company. Columbia/Riker, Bulletin for Town and County Runabout, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Electric Vehicle Company. Columbia/Riker, List of owners, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Description of the Riker 8 HP Gasoline Vehicle, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Operator’s license and 1st auto registration, Philadelphia, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Electric Vehicle Company. Columbia/Riker, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Riker Electric Vehicles, price list, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Riker Electric Vehicles, directions for care and management, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Riker Electric Vehicles, handbill, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Riker Electric Vehicles additional documents, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Company, engraving plate for A.L. Riker's business cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Riker Motor Vehicle Company, name plate, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Contract with A.L. Riker to develop 8 HP gasoline engine and car, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - License and Locomobile envelope, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - List of car specs, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Vanderbilt Cup instructions for entrants, 1905-1908 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Vanderbilt Cup banquet, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - A.L. Riker sales book and company address book, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Formula of steels used in construction of Locomobiles, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Ball bearings as an automobile sales factor by A.L. Riker, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Info sheet on A.L. Riker’s gunboat roadster, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Notes regarding periodicals and lists of articles appearing in, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Invoice for Locomobile converter for A.L. Riker, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Locomobile correspondence, 1902-1929 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Locomobile trademark registration, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Address to employees of Locomobile about flag raising, unknown author, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Additional notes and material relating to Locomobile, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series III: Patents issued to Andrew L. Riker
  - List of patents issued to Riker, 1886-1924 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Patent 711441, motor vehicle frames, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Patent 725990, internal combustion engines, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Patent 906290, spark adjusting means, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Patent 17499, improvements in internal combustion engines, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Patent 1051515 speed changing mechanism, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Patent 1108851, band breaks, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Patent 1109637, internal combustion engines, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Patent 1144433, internal combustion engines, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Patent 1156038, internal combustion engines, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Patent 1168421, controlling means for internal combustion engines, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Patent 1175813, controlling means for internal combustion engines, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Patent 1181252, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Patent 1206731, sparking connection for automobiles, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Patent 1213019, sparking device, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Patent 1215863, internal combustion engines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - U.S. Patent 1230033, internal combustion engine, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Patent 1244244, anti-skidding devices, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - U.S. Patent 1253630 internal combustion engine, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Assignment of Patent, A.L. Riker to Locomobile Company, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - U.S. Patent 1264561, power-transmission gearing, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Patent 1268623, internal combustion engines, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - U.S. Patent 1275173, windshields, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Patent 1326157, automobile breaks, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Patent 1368411, vehicle wheels, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - U.S. Patent 166218, ventilator, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Canadian patent 165623, internal combustion engines, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Canadian patent 166132, improvements to band brakes, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Patent 166945, regulation means for internal combustion engines, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Canadian Patent 167846. Improvements in internal combustion engines, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Canadian Patent 196941, automobile brakes, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Canadian Patent 203591, internal combustion engines, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - UK Patent 17499, Improvements in internal combustion engines, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - U.K. Patent 19507, improvements in band brakes, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - U.K. Patent 22197, improvements to ignition systems, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Automotive and aviation patents, 1924-1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Additional patents, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - A.L. Riker inventions, 1 of, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - A.L. Riker inventions, 2 of, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Series IV: Blueprints and drawings
  - Blueprint, layout of Elizabethport (Elizabeth, NJ) plant, 1895-1899 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Blueprint, style 86 electric, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Blueprint, gasoline car for Locomobile, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Early electrical drawings, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Blueprint, McCormick Automatic starter, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Drawing. Gasoline engine, Cooper Hewitt, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sketch, Speed launch for A.L. Riker, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Blueprints related to Rubber shock insulator company, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Blueprints related to gas engine for Charles E. Sargent, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Drawing, hub enclosed differential for Riker carriages, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Series V: Subject files
  - Constitution and by-laws of the Electrical Contractors Association, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Electrical fraternity dinner invitation, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Speech given to [?] club, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New York Electrical Society symposium, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Engineers club, annual report, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Automobile Club of America banquets, 1902-1903 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - American Motor League constitution and by-laws, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - May Carnival-Bridgeport Fresh Air Association, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - SAE membership list, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - SAE dinner menu, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Honors from Naval Consulting Board, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Flushing Institute Association dinner invitation, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - American Red Cross life membership certificate, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Society of Automotive Engineers, membership directory, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Founder member of the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps country club, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Navy Yard ID for Andrew L. Riker, 1910-1919 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Society of Automobile Engineers, membership roster, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - National Automobile Chamber of Commerce annual dinner, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - SAE annual dinner, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - SAE annual dinner program, January 8, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - SAE pamphlets, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Misc., undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Series VI: Medals and Ribbons -- Restricted
  - Columbus Day, empty, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vanderbilt Cup Commission, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt Cup Race, American Elimination Trial and Member Commission, empty, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - American Elimination Trial, Cup Race Judge, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt Cup Race, Judge of Weigh-in, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Automobile Meet, Atlantic City Automobile Club, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Empire City Track, 11th Automobile Race Meet, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Member 1906 Cup Commission. American Elimination Trial (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Automobile Club of Hartford Reliability Contest, Referee, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting, counselor, A.L, Riker, empty, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Locomobile Sales Convention, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 13th Annual Meeting of the Garden Club of America, Mrs. Riker, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Unknown medal, possibly relating to World War One, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Automobile Permit, Central Park, empty, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Dinner in honor of Locomobile of America, empty, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Series VII: Published materials collected by Andrew L. Riker
  - Book, The Electric Motor and Its Applications, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Duggin and Crossman house catalog, 1878 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - C&C electric motor Company catalogue and testimonial letters, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlet, "The triumph valveteen compound engine", 1891 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, "L’Electricien Revenue International de l’ Électricité", 1892 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Journal, "The Compass" volume 3 number, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Magazine, Cassier’s Magazine, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlet, "La Rouche System" electrical machinery catalogue, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlet, J.H. Williams and Co. catalogue of drop forgings, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlet, American Electric Vehicle Company, catalogue, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pamphlet, Eletro-Chemical Storage Battery Company, catalogue and price list, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlet, Walker Manufacturing Company, bound copies of testimonial letters, 1894-1896 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlet, Automobile Club of America Racing Rules, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Information sheet, Motor Vehicle Law, New Jersey, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Membership certificate, International Electrical Congress, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Program, Fifth Automobile Race and Meet, Yonkers, New York, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Pamphlet, Automobile Club of America, Sixth Annual Banquet Guest List, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Handbill, Spirit Hill Climb, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Firestone Progressive Locomotion, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Booklet, Who’s Who and What’s What in Gasoline, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Pipe-Hartford trucks 3 and ton truck specs, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pamphlet, Fischner Motor, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Booklet, Edison Storage Batteries for Submarines, dedicated to A.L. Riker by Miller Reese Hutchinson, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Information on Mechanical Vessels from Fuller Engineering Company, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - League to enforce invitation to convention, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - The Lubrication of Motorcars, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Naval Consulting Board of the United States by Llord N. Scott feat. Riker’s name on the cover, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet, The Dey Electric, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Charging of Two-Stroke Engines by W. Morgan, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gear Tooth Shapes from American Machinist, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Railless Trolley Traction, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Electrical Company early catalogues, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Institution of Automotive Engineers Library catalogue, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Telegraph Testimonial Catalogue, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Presentation images from Harrisburg F and M works, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - A Little Manual for Motorists, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Automobile Quarterly, subscription solicitation brochure, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The Baylis Company, Reaction brush Holder descriptive pamphlet, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Alexander, Barney, and Chapin electrical supply catalogue, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Flather machine tools, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - I.A.E. data sheets, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Series IX: Maps
  - World’s Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fairfield county, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Coast of Maine, eastern part, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Pilot road map for New England, 1908-1909 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Travelers Atlas, New England, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Road map, western Connecticut, C.S. Hammond Company, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Map of proposed highways by National Highway Association, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Victory map of Europe, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - AAA service station directory, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Map of Connecticut, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Railroads of Connecticut, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Travels of George Washington, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Latest map of the coast of Maine, western part, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Latest map of southern New Hampshire, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad map, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Latest road map of southern and northern Vermont, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - New York, Philadelphia, and Norfolk Time Schedule, 1889 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Topographical maps from Withrop H. Perry, 1 of 2, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
  - Map of the Street Railways of Connecticut, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Series X: Clippings
  - Vanderbilt Cup Race, clippings from 1958 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Postcards, Vanderbilt Cup Race, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, #16, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New York Sun, Interview with Riker, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper ad for exhibition of War Locomobile, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bridgeport Sunday Post, Riker’s appointment to Naval Advisory Board, 1910-1919 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Riker’s appointment to Naval Advisory Board, 1910-1919 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Bridgeport Sunday Post, A. L. Riker and Edith Riker world trip, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 8)